Lorenzo Fabbri

Summary

I am a PhD student at the Barcelona Institute for Global Health (ISGlobal). I work under the supervision of Prof. Martine Vrijheid. My main topic of interest is the use of modern Causal Inference methods to answer questions in the broad field of Environmental Neuroepidemiology. I am also profoundly interested in Open Science and Reproducible Research.

I received my Bachelor's degree in Biotechnology and my Master's degree in Quantitative and Computational Biology.

My personal webpage is here. You can also find me on Twitter, Bluesky, Mastodon, and GitHub.

Working Experience

PhD Student Barcelona Institute for Global Health (Barcelona, ES)	2021 - Present
Student Research Assistant Fellowship Università della Svizzera italiana (Lugano, CH)	2017 - 2017

Funding

-	
Meritatamente 2022 Società Unione Mutuo Soccorso (San Marino, SM)	2022
Erasmus+ Traineeship Programme Scholarship University of Trento (Trento, IT)	2019
Faculty of Informatics Scholarship Università della Svizzera italiana (Lugano, CH)	2016
Erasmus Traineeship Programme Scholarship University of Parma (Parma, IT)	2015

Honors and Awards

Outstanding Abstract by a Student	
International Society for Environmental Epidemiology	2022

Publications

- 1. Fabbri L, Garlantézec R, Audouze K, et al. Childhood exposure to non-persistent endocrine disrupting chemicals and multi-omic profiles: A panel study. Environment International. Published online February 26, 2023:107856. doi:10.1016/j.envint.2023.107856
- 2. Thiel C, Cordes H, Fabbri L, et al. A Comparative Analysis of Drug-Induced Hepatotoxicity in Clinically Relevant Situations. PLOS Computational Biology. 2017;13(2):e1005280. doi:10.1371/journal.pcbi.1005280

Conference Presentations

Childhood exposure to non-persistent endocrine disrupting chemicals and multi-omic profiles: a panel study

2022

-

 $\mathrm{Feb}\ 2017$

	TRUING EDUCATION
Childhood exposure to non-persistent endocrine disrupting chemicals and multi-omic markers in a population-based child cohort	222
	2022
ABCPy for PASC	0.001
	2021
Childhood exposure to non-persistent endocrine disrupting chemicals and multi-omic markers in a population-based child cohort	
markers in a population-based child colloit	2021
-	
Education	
PhD Programme in Biomedicine Universitat Pompeu Fabra (Barcelona, ES)	2021 - Present
M.Sc. in Quantitative and Computational Biology Università degli Studi di Trento (Trento, IT)	2017 - 2019
M.Sc. Student in Computational Science Università della Svizzera italiana (Lugano, CH)	2016 - 2017
B.Sc. in Biotechnology University of Parma (Parma, IT)	2012 - 2016
-	
Continuing Education	
Spring School in Causal Inference with Observational Data Causal Insights, Leeds (UK)	Apr 2022
Computational Bayesian methods using brms in R Physaliacourses, online	Feb 2022
ELIXIR Omics Integration and Systems Biology	
National Bioinformatics Infrastructure Sweden, online Fundamentals of Epidemiology (EPM101)	Sep 2021
LSHTM, online Advanced Statistics: Statistical Modelling	Sep 2021
Swiss Institute of Bioinformatics, online	Aug 2021
Alpine Exposome Summer School Inserm and ATHLETE, online	Jun 2021
Metabolomics Data Processing and Data Analysis University of Birmingham, online	Feb 2021
Mendelian Randomisation Imperial College London, online	May 2020
Image Analysis and Modeling of Complex Biological Dynamics University of Wurzburg, Wurzburg (DE)	Sep 2017
Effective High Performance Computing Summer School CSCS and University of Lugano, Lugano (CH)	Jul 2017

 $\begin{array}{l} {\bf MARVEL~School~on~Variationally~Enhanced~Sampling} \\ {\bf University~of~Lugano,~Lugano~(CH)} \end{array}$

University of Genova, Genoa (IT)	Nov 2015
Service	
Students and New Researchers Network International Society for Environmental Epidemiology	2022 - 2023
Early Career Scientist Working Group COnsortium of METabolomics Studies	2022 - 2022

Advanced Course in Alternatives to Animal Experimentation

 ${\bf SKILLS}$

Skills